I am on a wireless router and I'm trying to decide which type of network security, specifically which form of encryption, to use. Let's go through some of these choices.
WEP is Wired Equivalent Privacy. This form of encryption is considered weak as it has actually been cracked. Don't use this if you don't have to.
WPA is Wi-Fi Protected Access. This is much stronger than WEP and may be the strongest form of encryption you have available,
especially if the wireless access point you are configuring is old.
WPA2 is currently the strongest form of encryption and this should be used whenever possible. It is available on this wireless access point, so I will use it here.
Another option for securing wireless networks is to use the 802.11x option, also known as port-based network access control. This can be used for wireless or wired LANs.
802.11x has three pieces: the supplicant, the authenticator, and the network. Here is how this works. A remote client accesses a network remotely.
This client is known as the supplicant. Next, a router, known as an authenticator, alerts an authentication server,
such as a RADIUS server, to let it know a client wants to get on the network. The client will enter some credentials.
The server will verify those credentials and, if they are correct, will allow the client onto the network.